predictiveindex.com 2014-07-13

# Privacy Policy | PI Worldwide | Behavior and skill assessments, analytics, consulting services

**Privacy Policy for Praendex Incorporated  
doing business as PI Worldwide**

**Product User Privacy Policy  
**\- For customers and/or users including those invited to our websites to complete a PI® Survey or SSAT or use our e-learning system (collectively, “Users”)

**General Privacy Policy  
**\- For general visitors to our websites

**PI WORLDWIDE  
PRODUCT USER PRIVACY POLICY**

This Product User Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes the manner in which Praendex Incorporated, doing business as PI Worldwide (“PI Worldwide” or “we”), handles personal information collected in connection with the administration of its Predictive Index® proprietary management tool (the “Predictive Index” or “PI”), the Selling Skills Assessment Tool™ (the “SSAT”) and related management and sales training and access to its e-learning system. This includes personal information collected by the administration of The Predictive Index Organization Survey Checklist (“PI Survey”) or the SSAT (via web application, a local desktop application, or paper form), or usage of our e-learning system. In this Policy, the term ‘personal information’ means information that identifies, or can be used to identify, an individual.

This Policy does not describe PI Worldwide’s information collection practices with respect to its general corporate websites located at piworldwide.com and ssatsurvey.com. In this Policy, the term “Customer” means PI Worldwide’s corporate customers; the term “User” means employees, prospective employees and contractors of Customers, and those individuals who have access to our e-learning system, including but not limited to Licensees, Consultants, Analysts, Clients, and potential Clients.

Background  

PI Worldwide and its distributors provide Predictive Index-related services to Customers to help them align individual performance with specific business goals. The Predictive Index process is a combination of assessment, education and consulting. At the core of that process is the PI Survey, an assessment tool that provides insight into the natural workplace behaviors of employees and prospective employees, giving management valuable insights for coaching, leadership development, succession planning, employee selection, team performance and more. Normally, Customers administer the PI Survey to their Users. Users generally take the PI Survey online, via the _access_ PI™ web application, although Users may also take the PI Survey through a local desktop application, or by completing printed versions of the PI Survey. The educational component of the Predictive Index process involves training conducted by PI Worldwide and its distributors. Upon completion of the Predictive Index Management Workshop™ trainees (hereinafter “PI Analysts”) have received the necessary training to interpret and apply the Predictive Index. Whether the PI Survey is completed through the _access_ PI web application, a local desktop application or on paper, PI Worldwide’s software provides Customers with the results of the PI Survey, along with a basic report, which needs to be interpreted by a trained PI Analyst. In addition, PI Worldwide directly and through its distributors, provides consulting services to Customers to allow them to maximize the usefulness of the Predictive Index process.

PI Worldwide and its distributors also provide its Selling Skills Assessment Tool (SSAT) to Customers. The SSAT, available in over 20 industry- or job-specific editions, is an online survey of 25 targeted, scenario-based questions, which provides management with a detailed quantification of the selling skills possessed across their organization. The results provide Customers with sales force data, group data and individual data. Users have access to their own SSAT results and to a general comparative analysis of the SSAT results of the group of Customer employees in which they fall; Users do not have direct access to the SSAT results of any other User. In addition, PI Worldwide directly and through its distributors, provides sales training services to Customers to allow them to focus their sales training initiative for maximum impact. PI Worldwide also provides access to its e-learning system through a third-party server which provides information about the Predictive Index as well as questions at the end of each Module for the User to provide answers to various questions in order to assess his/understanding of the content.

PI Worldwide and its distributors also provide e-learning modules to Licensees, Associates, Analysts, Clients and potential Clients. The purpose of the e-learning system is to provide learning modules about the Predictive Index and the history of behavioral analytics, interpretation of the Survey and how to provide meaningful and appropriate feedback to those who take the Predictive Index Survey.

Safe Harbor  

PI Worldwide complies with the U.S.- EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  PI Worldwide has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view PI Worldwide’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

[ ** Click here ** ](http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=20089) to access the Safe Harbor List record of Praendex, Inc, d/b/a PI Worldwide. Should the URL change, our record can always be located by searching the [ ** Safe Harbor List ** ](https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx) .

Notice   
PI Worldwide will inform Users about the purposes for which it collects information about them, how to contact PI Worldwide with inquiries or complaints, the types of third parties to whom PI Worldwide discloses personal information, and the choices and means PI Worldwide offers Users for limiting use and disclosure of personal information. This notice is provided by means of this Policy, which is made available to Users before personal information is obtained from them.

Choice  
The Safe Harbor privacy principles require that PI Worldwide provide Users with the right to opt out as to whether personal information is disclosed to a third party (other than a third party acting as PI Worldwide’s agent or a third party software system used by the Customer or PI Worldwide), or used for a purpose that is incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the User. As PI Worldwide does not disclose personal information except to its agents or third party software systems used by the Customer or PI Worldwide (as described in the “Onward Transfer” section below) or to the Customer for the benefit of whom the User provided the information, and PI Worldwide does not use personal information for incompatible purposes, there are no activities for which an opt-out is applicable.

Notice: What Personal Information Does PI Worldwide Collect, and How Do We Use It?

_PI Survey  
_ When a PI Survey is administered via the _access_ PI web application or is otherwise entered into the _access_ PI web application, such as through the accessPI-CONNECT™ functionality or through a third party portal, PI Worldwide collects the following personal information about Users, which generally consists of the following and is used solely for the purpose of administering the Predictive Index, generating reports of the results, providing the results to the Customer, and interpreting the results for the Customer:

  * First and last name;
  * Occupation/title;
  * Email address; and
  * Responses to the PI Survey

The responses consist of the User’s reaction to a list of adjectives. Users of _access_ PI taking the survey through a remote, on-line portal are also required to provide a username and password. The password is application generated, but the username is the User’s email address.

In addition, Customers who use the _access_ PI or other online portal may optionally request and store other information from their Users including job code, department code, occupation, or other information. PI Worldwide does not make use of such information except in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

In conjunction with its research endeavors only, PI Worldwide may ask some Survey Takers to provide voluntarily their gender, age, country of origin, ethnic origin, educational level, and employment level. Any information so collected may be used for internal research purposes only, and will not be reflected in the assessment results nor disclosed to any third party.

_SSAT  
_ In administering the SSAT, PI Worldwide collects the following personal information from individuals who complete the survey, which is used solely for the purpose of administering the SSAT, generating reports of the results, providing the results to the Customer, and interpreting the results for the Customer:

  * First and last name and middle initial
  * Customer provided group designation such as region, district or department;
  * Email address; and
  * Responses to the SSAT

The responses consist of the User’s answers to 25 questions In addition, in the administration of the SSAT, PI Worldwide may collect other, optionally provided, personal information from individuals who complete the survey. This information, which, if entered by the User, is used by PI Worldwide for normative data and validity studies, is only reported to third parties as aggregated information. The other optionally provided information collected includes the following:

  * Current age
  * Total years of sales experience
  * Years of sales experience while employed by the Customer
  * Ethnic Origin
  * Gender; and
  * Highest level of education completed.

_e-learning system_  
In providing access to its e-learning system through a third party server, the following information is provided about the Users:

  * First and last name and middle initial
  * Addresses
  * PI username
  * Company name
  * Relationship to PI Worldwide
  * Title/occupation

_ Training and Education_

In addition to the information outlined above in the administration of the PI Survey, SSAT, and the e-learning system, PI Worldwide and its distributors collect additional personal information from PI Analysts and employees of Customers who attend sales training. This information includes address, telephone number and fax number.

_Onward Transfer: What Personal Information Does PI Worldwide Disclose to Third Parties?_

PI Worldwide does not sell or rent personal information to any third party. PI Worldwide does not disclose personal information of Users to any third parties except to fulfill the purposes for which the information was disclosed. To fulfill those purposes, we disclose personal information as follows:

  * To the Customer who administered or ordered the PI Survey or SSAT;
  * To employees of PI Worldwide, for the purposes of database management, administration and customer support, as well as providing assistance interpreting the PI Survey or SSAT results;
  * If the Customer in question purchased the Predictive Index or SSAT through one of our distributors, to that distributor and its employees and subcontractors, also for the purposes of management and administration, as well as providing assistance interpreting the PI Survey or SSAT results;
  * To subcontractors of PI Worldwide who are engaged in the development and management of our hardware, software and communications infrastructure or who otherwise assist PI Worldwide in database management, administration and customer  and User support and service;
  * To third party software systems used by the Customer; and
  * To the entity and its employees which purchased and/or use the e-learning system

All of the Customers, employees, distributors and subcontractors and third party software providers described above are subject to contractual or other legally binding obligations to comply with the requirements of this Policy. Because PI Worldwide adheres to the Safe Harbor privacy principles, all Customers, distributors and subcontractors that receive any personal information of Users in the European Union or Switzerland are either themselves subject to EU and Swiss data privacy law, the Safe Harbor Principles or another adequacy finding, or have entered into a written agreement with PI Worldwide requiring that such third party provide at least the same level of privacy protection as the Safe Harbor Principles.

_ Legal Disclaimers _  
PI Worldwide reserves the right to disclose personal information if required by law enforcement authorities, subpoena or other court order, or other governmental authority, and (to the extent permitted by law and the Safe Harbor principles) to the extent necessary to protect the legal rights and personal safety of PI Worldwide and its employees and agents.

_Security  
_ PI Worldwide maintains appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to ensure the security of personal information covered by this Policy, and to protect such personal information from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. PI Worldwide has a written data security policy that describes the policies and procedures by which data security is to be maintained.

_Data Integrity  
_ PI Worldwide does not process personal information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by the User. To the extent necessary for the purposes associated with PI Worldwide’s data collection, PI Worldwide takes reasonable steps to ensure that data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete and current.

_User Access to Personal Information  
_ If a User wishes to obtain access to personal information held by PI Worldwide about that User, in order to review, correct, amend or delete that information, the User should send a request to PI Worldwide in writing by:

  * Sending an email to our Privacy Officer, Mary Beth Cotter, J.D. at [legal@piworldwide.com](mailto:legal@piworldwide.com)
  * Sending postal mail to our Privacy Officer, Mary Beth Cotter, J.D., PI Worldwide, 16 Laurel Ave., Wellesley, MA, 02481, USA.

PI Worldwide will allow a User to review, correct, amend or delete personal information held by PI Worldwide about that User: (a) if the User is a resident of the European Union, to the extent such review, correction, amendment or deletion is required by the Safe Harbor privacy principles; or (b) otherwise, if the Customer on whose behalf the information was collected consents. PI Worldwide reserves the right to obtain proof of identity from the User. PI Worldwide may levy a reasonable administrative charge for User access to personal information as described in this paragraph.

_Enforcement of this Policy  
_ If you have a question, comment or complaint about this Policy or enforcement of this Policy, please address your concern to PI Worldwide in writing to:

Nancy J. Martini, President and CEO  
PI Worldwide  
16 Laurel Avenue  
Wellesley, MA 02481 USA

PI Worldwide will investigate your concerns promptly, and will respond to your correspondence within thirty (30) days after we receive it. PI Worldwide will provide you with a clear explanation of any decisions made with respect to your request. If you are not satisfied with the manner in which PI Worldwide dealt with your privacy concern, you may use an external recourse mechanism, as described below.

_EU and Swiss Residents_  
PI Worldwide has elected to satisfy its obligation under the Safe Harbor privacy principles to provide a readily available and affordable independent recourse mechanism, and to remedy problems arising out of any failure to comply with the Safe Harbor principles, by committing to cooperate with European and Swiss data protection authorities with respect to personal information about EU and Swiss Users held by PI Worldwide. PI Worldwide will cooperate with the European and Swiss data protection authorities in the handling and resolution of complaints brought under the Safe Harbor privacy principles. Any User who is resident in the EU or Switzerland should address his or her concerns to his or her local data protection authority.

_Non-EU or Switzerland Residents  
_If you are not a resident of the European Union or Switzerland, any dispute arising between a User and PI Worldwide with respect to this Product User Privacy Policy, including the breach, enforcement, interpretation or validity thereof, shall be resolved by binding arbitration conducted in Boston, Massachusetts by a single arbitrator. The arbitration shall be administered by JAMS pursuant to its Streamlined Arbitration Rules and Procedures. Judgment on the arbitration award may be entered in any court having jurisdiction. This clause shall not preclude parties from seeking provisional remedies in aid of arbitration from a court of appropriate jurisdiction.

Verification  
PI Worldwide conducts an annual self-assessment to verify that this Policy is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, completely implemented, accessible and conforms to the Safe Harbor principles, and to confirm that employee training and appropriate compliance procedures are in place.

General  
This Policy does not govern PI Worldwide’s collection and use of information that does not constitute personal information. Without limitation of the foregoing, PI Worldwide may collect, store and use aggregated, anonymous information from the administration of the PI Survey, SSAT and e-learning system in order to improve its business and the PI Survey and SSAT themselves. This information does not identify any individual. In addition, PI Worldwide uses log files and other generally available web tracking technologies in operating, maintaining and improving the _access_ PI™and SSAT websites. This information does not contain any personal information and is not linked to any personal information that PI Worldwide does hold. This Policy applies to PI Worldwide and to PI Worldwide’s distributors, who are independent third parties licensed to distribute the Predictive Index, SSAT, and e-learning system, and provide related management and sales training. PI Worldwide’s distributors have agreed in writing to comply with this Policy.

_Policy updated as of December, 2012_

**PI WORLDWIDE  
GENERAL PRIVACY POLICY**

This General Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes the manner in which Praendex Incorporated, doing business as PI Worldwide (“PI Worldwide” or “we”), handles personal information collected in connection with its public websites, including piworldwide.com, ssatsurvey.com, and _access_ PI.com,. PI Worldwide has established this Policy to protect the content of these websites, including all information provided by users of these sites, from unauthorized access, disclosure, or release. In this Policy, the term ‘personal information’ means information that identifies, or can be used to identify, an individual.

This Policy does not describe PI Worldwide’s information collection practices with respect to personal information collected in connection with the administration of its Predictive Index proprietary management tool (the “Predictive Index” or “PI”), the Selling Skills Assessment Tool (the “SSAT”) and related management and sales training, and access to its e-learning system, which are described in PI Worldwide’s Product User Privacy Policy.

Information Collection  
Praendex Incorporated is the sole owner of the information on this site and collected on this site. PI Worldwide collects information from visitors wishing to learn more about PI Worldwide and its products and services. This information is collected via an online form.

Information Use  
PI Worldwide will not sell, share, or rent collected information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

Profiles  
PI Worldwide does not create or maintain profiles of visitors to its sites.

Cookies  
PI Worldwide may elect to generate “cookies.”  The cookies we provide are retained by the user’s computer and stored on the user’s hard drive. These cookies are used to assist with login defaults (i.e., persistent cookies) and to maintain session state during use of our secure applications (i.e., session cookies) and to track activity on the Company’s site (tracking cookies). All of the cookies generated by PI Worldwide, and the information inside is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information. These cookies are used only for the purpose of improving the User experience. Users may reject a cookie with an understanding that access to and use of the site may be severely limited.

We may use session ID cookies and/or persistent cookies when a connection is made to one of our applications. For the session cookie, once a user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is available for use for an extended period of time. The user can remove persistent cookies by following the directions in his/her Internet browser’s help files.

Third Party Advertising  
These sites do not contain any third party advertising.

Log Files  
Like most standard web servers we use log files. This includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Our objective is to monitor the quality of the user experiences on our sites. IP addresses, and other log information, are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Communications from the Site  
The only communications resulting from this site are responses to visitor requests for additional information. Communications may be via phone, email, or postal mail in accordance with the visitor’s preferences.

Sharing  
Non-Personally Identifiable Information (Aggregate)  
We may share aggregated demographic information for the purpose of maintaining and expanding these sites and their contents.

Personally Identifiable Information (Aggregate)  
Personally identifiable information includes name, company, address, phone, email, and other information gathered by online form from visitors wishing to be contacted with additional information. To respond to the visitor’s request, this information may be shared with employees of PI Worldwide as well as with PI Worldwide’s distributors and their employees and subcontractors.

_Legal Disclaimers_

PI Worldwide reserves the right to disclose personal information if required by law enforcement authorities, subpoena or other court order, or other governmental authority, and (to the extent permitted by law and the Safe Harbor principles) to the extent necessary to protect the legal rights and personal safety of PI Worldwide and its employees and agents.

Links  
These websites contain links to other sites owned and operated by PI Worldwide and/or its member companies. These sites may have privacy policies that differ from this site. This Policy applies solely to information collected by the websites referenced above.

Security  
These websites take commercially reasonable and generally accepted precautions to protect our personally identifiable information. When users submit sensitive information via these websites, the information is protected both online and off-line. Requested information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry – SSL. While on a secure page, such as our contact form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’. While we use encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also follow generally accepted and commercially reasonable policies and procedures to protect personal information off-line. Personal information is restricted in our offices with access limited to employees who need the information to perform a specific job. Employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Periodically, as well as any time new policies are added, employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance placed on privacy, and what employees can do to ensure personal information is protected. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a monitored environment. If you have any questions about the security of these websites, you can send an email to [ techsupport@piworldwide.com ](mailto:techsupport@piworldwide.com) .

Correcting/Updating Personal Information  
If your personally identifiable information changes, updated information may be provided to us at any time.

Notification of Changes  
Changes to this Policy will be posted on this site. We will use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy version under which the information was collected.

_Policy updated as of December, 2012._
